Guide to the Ronald Shiffman collection on the Pratt Center for Community Development 2013.023
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 3: Community Development
  - Sub-series 3.4: Building Hope Audio-Visual Recordings
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union, Esteban Tores, The East Los Angeles Community Union HQ; The Woodlawn Organization, Lauren Allen and Jeannette Branch -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 088)
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union, Kemp #1-3, undated (Box 121, Item 062)
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union, Kemp #3-6, undated (Box 121, Item 063)
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union, Liz Arraga, undated (Box 121, Item 066)
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union, Liz-Arraga, undated (Box 120, Item 056)
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union, Torres #1-2, undated (Box 125, Item 123)
    - The East Los Angeles Community Union: Scholarship Fund Program, undated (Box 121, Item 064)
    - Elsie Richardson #3, Ron Shiffman #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, 1998 (Box 140, Item 470)
      VHS. Runtime: 0:49:24
    - Elsie Richardson Walk with Kennedy, undated (Box 131, Item 221)
      VHS.
    - Fr Kennedy; Sheel Trapp; Dave Knotb, undated (Box 142, Item 427)
    - Garcia Interview -- PICCED, undated (Box 140, Item 325)
    - Harlem Commonwealth Council, undated (Box 127, Item 151)
    - Harlem Commonwealth Council, undated (Box 127, Item 152)
    - Harlem Commonwealth Council, undated (Box 127, Item 150)
    - Harlem Commonwealth Council, James Dowdy #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 175)
    - Harlem Commonwealth Council, James Dowdy #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 176)
    - Huelga, undated (Box 120, Item 060)
      U-matic. Runtime: 0:20:00
    - Huelga 1 of 2, undated (Box 120, Item 057)
    - Huelga 2 of 2, undated (Box 131, Item 214)
    - Interviews with Gary Hattem, David Dinkins, Elise Richardson; Pratt B-Roll; Interview with Eva Hanhardt, Brian Sullivan, 2003 (Box 142, Item 441)
    - Jeremy Nowak, undated (Box 136, Item 292)
    - Jeremy Nowak #1-3, undated (Box 135, Item 267)
    - Jeremy Nowak #4-6, undated (Box 135, Item 268)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, undated (Box 119, Item 034)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, undated (Box 134, Item 239)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Juan Patlan #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oraln History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 005)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Juan Patlan #3, and Miscellaneous Visuals -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 006)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Mahula, undated (Box 118, Item 014)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Mahula, undated (Box 118, Item 015)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Patlan, undated (Box 118, Item 012)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Patlan, undated (Box 118, Item 013)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Royce Mahula #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 003)
    - Mexican American Unity Council, Royce Mahula #2, and Juan Patlan #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 004)
    - Michael Kane, undated (Box 141, Item 328)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 128, Item 171)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 153)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 154)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 158)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 159)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 160)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 128, Item 163)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 128, Item 164)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 128, Item 165)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 128, Item 166)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 125, Item 143)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 125, Item 144)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 125, Item 145)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 146)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 147)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 148)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, undated (Box 127, Item 149)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Betty Jo Hinds and Malcolm Walls -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 184)
      BetacamSP. Runtime: 1:00:00
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Blackwell, undated (Box 127, Item 157)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Congressman Mike Espy, Councilman Charles Moore, and Mayor Earl Lucas -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 181)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Ed Brown #1, undated (Box 128, Item 161)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Ed Brown #2, undated (Box 128, Item 162)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Ed Brown #2 and Larry Farmer #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 178)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Ed Brown #3, undated (Box 128, Item 167)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Ed Brown #4, undated (Box 128, Item 168)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Ed Brown #5, undated (Box 128, Item 169)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Farmer, undated (Box 127, Item 155)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Farmer, undated (Box 127, Item 156)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Governor Ray Maybus, Delta Blues Festival and James 'Son' Thomas -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 183)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Larry Farmer #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 180)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Mayor Frank Self, Tour of Metcalfe, Charles Taylor, and Tour of Fine Vinces, Inc. -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 142)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Mayor S.L. Lindsey and Mayor Walter Lee McDavid -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 182)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Metcalfe B-Roll, undated (Box 128, Item 174)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Unita Blackwell #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 177)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, Unita Blackwell #2 and Ed Brown #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 179)
    - Mississippi Action for Community Education, We Honor Him Most, 1992 (Box 128, Item 170)
    - National Council of La Raza, Raul Yzaguirre -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 011)
    - New Community Corporation #1-3, undated (Box 133, Item 222)
    - New Community Corporation #4-6, undated (Box 133, Item 223)
    - New Community Corporation #7-8, undated (Box 133, Item 224)
    - New Community Corporation, Rev. Monsignor, William J. Linder -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 001)
    - New Community Corporation, William J. Linder #2, "Town Meeting", St. Joseph's Plaza, Harmony House, Babyland, undated (Box 117, Item 002)
    - Overview F. Jones Interview, undated (Box 131, Item 217)
    - Overview Yates and Jones Interview, undated (Box 131, Item 218)
    - Overview Yates Interview, undated (Box 131, Item 219)
    - Raul Yzaguirre 1, 2, 3, undated (Box 120, Item 058)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, undated (Box 122, Item 111)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, undated (Box 122, Item 112)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, undated (Box 122, Item 113)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, undated (Box 120, Item 055)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, Brown #1-2, undated (Box 118, Item 020)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, Brown #3-4, undated (Box 119, Item 039)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, Brown #5, undated (Box 118, Item 021)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, Harriet Tubman Apartments, Sojourner Apartments, and Sojourner Community Center -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 124, Item 106)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, John Brown Jr #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 138)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, John Brown Jr #2 and Miscellaneous Interviews -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 139)
    - Southeast Alabama Self-Help Association, Mary B. McCall -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 140)
    - Southeast Community Organization, Betty Hyatt #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 009)
    - Southeast Community Organization, Betty Hyatt #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 010)
    - Southeast Community Organization, Robert Giloth #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 007)
    - Southeast Community Organization, Robert Giloth #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 117, Item 008)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, undated (Box 118, Item 022)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, undated (Box 118, Item 023)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, undated (Box 133, Item 229)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Baltimore Harbor, undated (Box 118, Item 019)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Baltimore Harbor, undated (Box 118, Item 024)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Gillof, undated (Box 118, Item 025)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Gillof, undated (Box 118, Item 026)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Gillof, undated (Box 119, Item 038)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Hyatt #3-4, undated (Box 118, Item 027)
    - Southeast Development Incorporated, Hyatt Interview #1-2, undated (Box 119, Item 035)
    - Southern Development Corporation, Marvin Beauvalier, United Bank Board Members -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 136)
    - Southern Development Corporation, Miscellaneous Visuals from Southern Development Foundation Farm and Zydeco Festival -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 137)
    - Southern Development Corporation, Rev A.J. McKnight #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 124, Item 109)
    - Southern Development Corporation, Rev A.J. McKnight #3 and Wilbert Guillory -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 124, Item 110)
    - Southern Development Corporation, Rev. A.J. McKnight #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 124, Item 105)
    - Southern Development Fund, undated (Box 118, Item 016)
    - Southern Development Fund, undated (Box 118, Item 018)
    - Southern Development Fund, undated (Box 119, Item 028)
    - Southern Development Fund, undated (Box 119, Item 029)
    - Southern Development Fund, undated (Box 119, Item 036)
    - Southern Development Fund, undated (Box 119, Item 037)
    - Southern Development Fund, Beaulieu, undated (Box 118, Item 017)
    - Southern Development Fund, McKnight, undated (Box 119, Item 030)
    - Southern Development Fund, McKnight, undated (Box 119, Item 031)
    - Southern Development Fund, McKnight, undated (Box 119, Item 032)
    - Southern Development Fund, McKnight, undated (Box 119, Item 033)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, undated (Box 125, Item 120)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, undated (Box 133, Item 226)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Arabella Martinez #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 133)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Gallegos, undated (Box 125, Item 127)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Gallegos, undated (Box 125, Item 117)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Henry Mestre -- Community Development Corporations Oral History, undated (Box 126, Item 131)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Henry Mestre #2, Arabella Martinez #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 132)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Herman Gallegos -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 124, Item 103)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Isabella Martinez #3 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 126, Item 134)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Lee Turner, Muecke, De Colores Childrens' Campus, Villa Allegre, Posada de Colores, undated (Box 124, Item 104)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Martinez, undated (Box 125, Item 129)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Martinez, undated (Box 125, Item 119)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Mestre, undated (Box 125, Item 128)
    - Spanish Speaking Unity Council, Mestre, undated (Box 125, Item 118)
    - The Pratt Center -- Building Hope, 1993 (Box 131, Item 220)
      U-matic. Runtime: 0:47:00
    - United Durham Incorporated, undated (Box 121, Item 071)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Garrett Interview, undated (Box 121, Item 072)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Garrett Interview, undated (Box 121, Item 073)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Nathan Taylor Garrett #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 100)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Nathan Taylor Garrett #2 and Richmond Edward Stewart #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 101)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Richmond Edward Stewart #2 and Miscellaneous Visuals -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 102)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Stewart Interview, undated (Box 121, Item 074)
    - United Durham Incorporated, Stewart Interview, undated (Box 121, Item 075)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, undated (Box 131, Item 209)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, undated (Box 130, Item 190)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, undated (Box 130, Item 191)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, Homeless Shelter, Ted Watkins #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 097)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, Ted Watkins #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 096)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, Teryl Watkins #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 098)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, Teryl Watkins #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 099)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, Watkins, undated (Box 121, Item 068)
    - Watts Labor Community Action Committee, Watkins, undated (Box 121, Item 069)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, undated (Box 121, Item 076)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, undated (Box 122, Item 079)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, undated (Box 122, Item 080)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, undated (Box 122, Item 081)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, undated (Box 122, Item 082)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, undated (Box 122, Item 083)
    - The Woodlawn Organization File Tape, 1983 (Box 121, Item 065)
      U-matic. Runtime: 0:05:00
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Allen, undated (Box 122, Item 077)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Arthur Brazier #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 090)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Arthur Brazier #2, Ernest Jenkins, Carole Millison, and Weldon Beverly -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 091)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Brazier, undated (Box 122, Item 078)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Finney, undated (Box 121, Item 070)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Finney, undated (Box 122, Item 086)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Finney #1-2, undated (Box 122, Item 084)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Finney #3-4, undated (Box 122, Item 085)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Lauren Allen, Jeannette Branch -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project; The East Los Angeles Community Union, Esteban Torres -- The East Los Angeles Community Union HQ, undated (Box 126, Item 135)
      Betacam SP NTSC. Runtime: 1:00:00
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Leon Finney #1 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 092)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Leon Finney #2 -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 093)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Leon Finney #3 and Steering Committee Meeting -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 123, Item 094)
    - The Woodlawn Organization, Monica Bosker, Otis Jones, and Cutaways of Woodlawn -- Community Development Corporations Oral History project, undated (Box 123, Item 095)
    - The Woodlawn Organization: Brazier Interview, undated (Box 121, Item 067)
    - Zion Investment Association, undated (Box 130, Item 202)
    - Zion Investment Association, undated (Box 130, Item 203)
    - Zion Investment Association, undated (Box 128, Item 188)
    - Zion Investment Association, Leon Sullivan -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 129, Item 185)
    - Zion Investment Association, OIC Historical Marker Ceremony, Bob Nelson and Miscellaneous Visuals -- Community Development Corporations Oral History Project, undated (Box 132, Item 201)
    - Zion Investment Association, Sullivan, undated (Box 128, Item 187)
    - Zion Investment Association, Sullivan, undated (Box 130, Item 189)
- Series 4: Reports and Publications
  This series includes reports and publications from the Pratt Center, affiliated organizations, foundations, and others, primarily from the 1970s to the 1990s. Publications from the Pratt Center represent the wide variety of projects and research undertaken by the Center, including studies of housing, neighborhoods and public space throughout Brooklyn, analyses of neighborhoods and housing programs, and manuals on day care centers and housing resources. Other topics represented in the Pratt Center publications include commercial rent control, displacement, homelessness, manufacturing land use, parks, and zoning. This series includes Community Information Bulletins, published by the Pratt Center to alert the community to developments in urban renewal, housing and planning., as well as early issues of City Limits, a publication created from the merger of individual newsletters from the Pratt Center, the Urban Homesteading Assistance Board, and the Association of Neighborhood Housing Developers. Publications from affiliated organizations address similar topics, as well as rehabilitation and revitalization, the Brooklyn waterfront, small businesses, and subway service. The majority of foundation reports and publications are from the Ford Foundation. Significant topics represented by foundation reports include urban and rural poverty, and community development.
  - Sub-series 4.1: Pratt Center
    - A Study of the Rent-Regulated Multi-family Rental Housing Stock in: Central Harlem, Bushwick, Ocean Hill-Brownsville, Morris Heights, 1993-1995 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - American Institute of Architects Miscellaneous 1996-1998 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - An Evaluation of the Neighborhood Development Demonstration, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 4-5)
    - Articles about PICCED, 1979-2008 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Best Practices, 1997-2000 (Box 56, Folder 6-8)
    - Breaking New Ground Background Materials, 1994-1996 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Brooklyn Sports Study Phase 1: Locational Analysis, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Commercial Rent Control, 1984-1985 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Committee for Housing New York, 1980-1985 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Community Attitudes in Bedford-Stuyvesant, 1967 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Community Information Manual, Central Brooklyn Edition, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 3-4)
    - Community Information Bulletins, 1961-1981 (Box 69, Folder 9-12, Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Consortium for Worker Education, 2000-2002 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Contract with America and Planning, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Deghettoization, circa 1960s (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Development and Preservation of Identity, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Development Commitments Study Commission, 1983-1984 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Developments Commitments Study Commission 1983, 1975-2001 (Box 57, Folder 10-11)
    - Director Brad Lander Opinion Articles, 2008-2016 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Displacement Pressure on the Lower East Side, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Emergency Committee on Housing, Community Development, and Homelessness, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Evaluation of Title I (ESEA) Programs -- Williamsburg Performing Arts Center, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Flyers, 1992, 2017 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Harlem Brownstone: Harlem Urban Development Corporation Rehabilitation Cost Analysis, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Herbert Von King Park Neighborhood Study, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 2-3)
    - Homeless Housing and Assistance Program Development, 1992 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Hon. Robert F. Kennedy -- If Men do not Build, How Shall They Live?, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Housing Funding, Homesteading, Reagan Budget Cuts, 1981 (Box 58, Folder 6-7)
    - Housing Resource Manual, 1979 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Housing Resource Manual, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Impact of a Housing Voucher Program on New York City's Population, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
    - Land Use and Building Condition Survey, 1989 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Lessons in Community-Based Planning: The Case of Red Hook, Brooklyn, New York, 1996 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Making it in New York: Manufacturing Land Use and Zoning Initiative, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Making it in New York: Manufacturing Land Use and Zoning Initiative, 2001 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Making it in New York: Manufacturing Land Use and Zoning Initiative, Yale, 2003 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Manual on Day Care Centers in New York City, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Market Analysis of Fifth Avenue Commercial Corridor, 1983 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Materials for Whitney M. Yung Jr. Nomination Submission, 1988 (Box 109, Folder 3)
    - Mayor's Panel on Affordable Housing, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Metropolis: The Sandlot Education, 1997 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Community Economic Development, 1979-1989 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - NCCED National Congress for Community Economic Development, 1992-1997 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Neighborhood Planning for Housing Organizations Part II, 1996 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Neighborhood Survey: Land Use, Building Condition and Streetscape, East End Historic District, 1996 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - New Roofs for a New Century Conference, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 9)